{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which group of plants has the greatest diversity (i.e. the most species) living today?", "opta": "Bryophyta", "optb": "Lycophyta", "optc": "Gymnosperms", "optd": "Angiosperms", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which group of land plants is most restricted to moist environments?", "opta": "Lycophyta", "optb": "Sphenophyta", "optc": "Bryophyta", "optd": "Angiosperms", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What single feature is probably most responsible for the success of angiosperms?", "opta": "Seeds", "optb": "Fruit", "optc": "Broad leaves", "optd": "Flowers", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Auxanometer is used for measuring", "opta": "respiratory activity", "optb": "photosynthetic activity", "optc": "growth activity", "optd": "osmotic pressure", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In angiosperm, the endosperm is", "opta": "haploid", "optb": "diploid", "optc": "triploid", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Gypsum is beneficial for", "opta": "phosphorus enriched soil", "optb": "water logged soil", "optc": "alkaline soil", "optd": "saline soil", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The study of interaction between living organism and environment is called", "opta": "ecosystem", "optb": "phytogeography", "optc": "ecology", "optd": "photosociology", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Lichen involves two organisms as", "opta": "virus and bacteria", "optb": "algae and bacteria", "optc": "algae and fungi", "optd": "fungi and mosses", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A very common mutualistic, symbiotic relationship between a fungus and the roots of a plant is", "opta": "lichen", "optb": "mycorrhizal", "optc": "ascomycete", "optd": "basidiomycete", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Archaeabacteria differ from the true bacteria as they have", "opta": "different cell membrane lipids", "optb": "cell wall composition", "optc": "ribosomal RNA structure", "optd": "growth not inhibited by antibiotics", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the bundle sheath of C4 plant __________ is/ are less than mesophyll.", "opta": "PSI", "optb": "PSII", "optc": "PSI or PSII", "optd": "PSI and PSII", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Triticale is derived by crossing", "opta": "wheat and rice", "optb": "wheat and tapioca", "optc": "rye (secale) and wheat", "optd": "rye and rice", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The major source of sugar in the world is", "opta": "watermelon", "optb": "beetroot", "optc": "sugarcane", "optd": "dates", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Triticale, the first man made cereal is an example of", "opta": "artificial allopolyploidy", "optb": "artificial autopolyploidy", "optc": "man made crossing", "optd": "artificial evolution", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Mycorrhizae are symbiotic associations between", "opta": "algae and fungi", "optb": "root and fungi", "optc": "bacteria and root", "optd": "bacteria and fungi", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The proteins that forms the walls of the microtubules are", "opta": "actin", "optb": "tubulin", "optc": "pectin", "optd": "hydroxyproline", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The colour of flower is due to the presence of", "opta": "chlorophyll", "optb": "xanthophylls", "optc": "florigen", "optd": "chromoplast or anthocyanin", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are the names of the two genders of haploid yeast cells?", "opta": "A and Alpha", "optb": "M and F", "optc": "Y(a)and Y(b)", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Neurospora is used as an experimental tool in", "opta": "ecology", "optb": "cytology", "optc": "genetics", "optd": "physiology", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The volume of O2 liberated in photosynthesis has which of the following ratio to CO2?", "opta": "1:1", "optb": "2:1", "optc": "1:2", "optd": "3:1", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Rice can grow in water submerged soil because the plants", "opta": "have spongy roots", "optb": "can oxidize the micro-environment around their roots and thus able to absorb oxygen", "optc": "are adapted to enable roots to ward off toxic products", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Who among the following coined the term Biotechnology?", "opta": "Karl Ereky", "optb": "James Clarke", "optc": "Paul Terasaky", "optd": "Clarke and Sommer", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}